# **MARIANNE GAA**

mariannegaa@gmail.com (438) 777-4887 Toronto, Ontario Website | LinkedIn | GitHub

## PROFILE

Academic background in statistics, research and project design. Self-taught programmer through Udemy and Codecademy coursework, StackOverflow resources, and a lot of trial and error. Resilient to frustration, detail-oriented and inspired by challenging problems. Bilingual in English and French. Looking to break into a **Data Analyst** role.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

MS Excel, VBA, HTML, CSS, SQL, Python Programming, Automation, Pandas, Matplotlib, Numpy, Statistics, Data Visualization, Jupyter Notebooks, Tableau, Git, Github and Command Line.

## **EDUCATION**

GradCert International Development, Humber College, 2017 Toronto BA Psychology, Brock University, 2014 St. Catharines

#### CERTIFICATES

Excel from Beginner to Advanced, Udemy, 2020

MySQL for Data Analytics and Business Intelligence, Udemy, 2020

Automate the Boring Stuff with Python Programming, Udemy, 2020

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Kampai Garden, Hostess, 2018 — 2019 Montreal

- Client-facing role in a fast-paced environment, ensured cohesive operation of service while providing an enjoyable guest experience
- Coordinated a diverse team to reduce turnaround time between services to 15 minutes in order to maximize capacity and business
- Liaison between guests and management, responsible for promptly addressing all requests and concerns, with a proven ability to multitask

# West Africa Network for Peace Building, Reporting & Communications Assistant, 2017 — 2018 Ghana

- Relationship building within the community through strategic communications
- Designed communications for distribution in collaboration with the Plan International team, expanding reach of conflict prevention programs to Ghana's youth demographic
- Summarization of key insights of projects and activities for the National Director and partner organization, The Fund for Peace
- Contributed to the organization's Annual Report 2016 and provided regional updates on conflicts within Ghana's mining communities for the National Action Plan 2018

# HRG Inc., Customer Service Representative, 2014 — 2016 Montreal

- Very technical and detail oriented role, exchanging airfare through back end software which required excellent problem solving in challenging situations
- Proven track record for eliminating surcharges from airlines by heeding airfare exchange rules meticulously
- Exceptional statistics related to call handing and efficiency